Ricardo Frías Fernández

About me

Videogame developer with experience in Unity3D and Unreal Engine, specialised in the field of programming with C#, C++ and blueprints.

Used to working with agile methodologies, great communication skills, teamwork and quick problem solving. Respectful, reliable and with a strong interest in broadening my knowledge.

Contact: r.friasfernandez@outlook.com | Linkedin | Itch.io | +34669430441

Experience

Videogame developer (Unreal Engine) | Oct. 2023 - curr.

Stardew Crossing | Personal project

- Solo developer in Unreal Engine
- Code in Blueprints and C++
- Mix of 2D and 3D elements

Videogame programmer (Unity3D) | Nov. 2021 - Mar. 2022

Katedral Studios | Remote

- Write code (C#) to implement design ideas
- Writing documentation about new mechanics and progress
- Work hand in hand with design department to iterate over new ideas

QA tester in productivity web application | Nov. 2022 - Oct. 2023

Life At | Remote

- Bug report and feedback
- · Regular meetings to update and share new ideas
- Testing of new feature before publishing

• Skills

- C#|C++/Blueprints|GDScript
- Unity3D|Unreal Engine|Godot
- Git
- Gameplay programmer
- Game Design
- UX | UI
- Microsoft Office

GameJams projects

- Global Game Jam Valencia (2023 & 2024)
- Universal Arts School (2022 & 2023)
- Universidad Europea de Madrid
 (2018 & 2019(staff))

Education

Master in videogame programming

(Unity3D & Unreal Engine) | Universal Arts School Valencia, Spain 2022-2024

Degree in videogame creation and design

Universidad Europea de Madrid *Madrid, Spain| 2018-2022*

Degree in Biomolecular science

Canterbury Christ Church University (2 years)

Canterbury, UK | 2016–2018

Languages Extra Spanish Driving license English Own car

Relocation

Galician

Other interests

Enviromental volunteering:

Croatia(2024), Cabo Verde (2023), Spain(2021, 2019), Thailand(2018), Nepal (2016)

Sports: Scuba, Ski, Padel